All right, so you
now know the basics
of packaging a video
to appeal to your
viewers, so they want
to tear it open
to watch the video
inside. Now what we
need to do is
look at the video's
box that's inside the
wrapping paper, because if
they don't like the
box, they're going to
leave. So the video's
box is known as
a format, and a
format is basically a
different type of video.
And what you'll find
is different viewers like
different types of formats.
And the name of
the game here, like
everything else we do,
is to try out
some of these formats,
or all of them,
and then when we
see signs of videos
bringing in viewers, sales,
conversions, we repeat more
of that over and
over again. So what
I've done is, when
you get to the
planning and the writing
modules, is I've produced
templates and guides for
every single type of
format that I want
you to try out,
and you will then
use those to create
your own versions. But
now what I'm going
to do is just
give you a quick
rundown of what each
of these things are.
And what that means
is, when you get
into the research stages
next, you kind of
need to spot, ah,
the pattern here is
deep dives. Ah, the
pattern here is they
love process. Ah, the
love listicles. So we're
just going to look
at the very basics
now. And let's start
off with a deep
dive. So what is
a deep dive? A
deep dive is basically
a video that's over
25 minutes long, that
kind of lays out
a system or a
process to get a
result. That's what I'm
clarifying as. So this
deep dive here is
the most profitable video
I have ever made.
At the time of
filming, it did 263
,000 views. That's $1
,000. Then we have
Simon Squibb. He did
this two and a
half hour deep dive,
13 million views, where
he just laid out
basically how to grow
a business. And then
you'll see shorter deep
dives too, but they're
often like masterclasses, ultimate
guides, step by step
systems. So that is
a deep dive. Now,
the pros of these
are they can build
a ton of credibility
because people just keep
watching you for longer,
engulf all that information
and start to trust
you more. Which then
in turn warms your
viewers up for sales.
It can then drive
really high conversions too.
And think of it
like this. Deep dives
attract more committed viewers
because if you're not
that interested in the
topic, you're probably not
going to click on
a 90 minute video.
Now the cons are
can be very time
intensive to produce and
they're risky for beginners.
If you put it
out and you don't
get many views, it's
going to feel very
costly because you've spent
a lot of time
on this. So it
can be a bit
more stressful. But also,
if you're new, just
think about this. Why
would a cold viewer
who's never heard of
you click on your
video that's 90 minutes
long? Like they probably
need something shorter to
build that little bit
of trust up with
first. So those are
kind of the negative
sides of a deep
dive. And if I
were to score them,
they can be amazing
for views. So I'll
give them a four
out of five for
sales. It's basically a
webinar. Like they're incredible
for conversion and they're
really strong for trust
building. All right. The
next type of video
I call a short
process. And this is
basically a 10 to
20 minute video that
lays out just a
very specific step by
step process to get
a result. So you
can see the. These
videos on screen, they're
all mine right now
and they're all a
very similar length, very
similar thumbnail style, pretty
much the same title.
All have amazing views.
And all I'm doing
is giving them very
basic information that doesn't
really ever go that
deep, but it just
lays out some steps
and they can be
very powerful. Now, the
pros of these are
again, when people see
a video that makes
it feel like it's
easy to get a
result using a very
simple system. Your credibility
goes. They have been
amazing for sales to
like these. I couldn't
quite believe how much
income these have generated.
So they're great for
conversion. They're also kind
of easy to make,
if I'm honest. When
the first one works,
I just turned it
into a template and
I basically repeat the
same thing over and
over again with slightly
different information in each
one and they're bingeable,
which I don't know
if I spell that
right.
Cons your viewers might
not actually want a
process. Some people don't
want that. But also
your viewers might want
something that's a bit
more in depth. When
I released these videos
to start, I was
actually a little bit
afraid that they were
too basic, but the
results speak for themselves.
We got it right.
So the score for
these, they're amazing for
views. They're great for
sales and they're good
for trust building. I
highly recommend. The next
style we've got is
a listicle. So a
listicle is pretty much
most videos on YouTube
where all people do
is they just list
points that are not
necessarily connected step by
step. So the first
video I'm going to
get you to make
is going to be
a listicle and this
video here is just
me saying 25 different
lessons I'd learned this
one here is like
top five exercises for
people to play and
this is Meadow here
who we're using as
an example again. She's
got her five clues
to spot a covert
narcissist. So it's just
listing information really. Now
the pros of these
are they're kind of
easier to make. They
keep people curious. So
you don't know what's
coming next. What that
means is we can
re -hook people when
the next point makes
them go, huh, this
sounds interesting. They are
just tried and tested
for views. And what
you find is people
only need one little
nugget, one little lesson
from a video they
don't need all five
where they can suddenly
have this light bulb
moment and then they
highly value you. Cons,
crowded field listicles. Everyone's
making them. They don't
necessarily differentiate you. They
don't promise a specific
result a lot of
the time and certain
avatars and viewer types,
they really want specific
results and process. I've
also found they're not
necessarily as great for
sales from my experience.
So I'm not saying
don't make these. They're
bad for sales. But
for me, when I
look at the conversion
data, the short process
and deep dives and
another video I'm going
to show in a
second, those are the
ones that made me
more money than the
listicles. So if I
was to score them,
they get a three
for views, three for
sales and a three
for trust building. But
that's based on me.
You find some channels,
these are a five
on all of them.
So the next style
is a roast. Now,
a roast is basically
where you kind of
critique, review and then
fix problems that people
have in your videos.
It could be a
viewers. It could be
someone who's not a
viewer. It could be
someone famous. So this
video here, I asked
my viewers to send
in their intros and
I played them and
then went, this is
what's wrong with them
and then showed them
how to fix it.
We've got other people
who are studying, maybe
celebrities who have reinvented
themselves, so it's not
viewers and then giving
their own personal opinion
on that. And then
we have Saad here.
Who did a similar
thing to me. He
reviewed people's commissions. So
roasts are really good
for sales. I am
talking really good, like
dollar per view on
these things. They are
next level. They're also
incredible for building your
credibility, because if you
make it in the
way I teach you,
you literally show your
viewers how to fix
the problem. And that
makes them go, wow,
this person's makes it
so easy. How can
they help me? So
they drive really high
conversions, much easier and
faster to make than
a video. And then
you have the other
people who are really
good at building your
credibility, because you're just
using your own expertise
to look at something
and point out what's
wrong. They're very bingeable.
They are really good
at growing your email
lists. And I'll teach
you how to do
that later on in
the program. They build
community and they differentiate
you. There's so many
people on YouTube just
repurposing blog posts or
other videos. This will
make you look very
unique because it is
undeniable proof of credibility.
Cons? Well, you kind
of want something visual
to roast.
It's very hard to
point out a mistake.
You will also find
that views will be
lower. Now they can
perform well, but it's
not likely going to
be the game changer
for you. And then
the other downside is
smaller channels might struggle
to harness this. The
way I teach to
do it is we
get our viewers to
get involved in this
to create the sense
of community. So if
you don't have any
viewers yet, it's going
to be harder to
utilize. So if I
was going to score
these bad boys, views
is lower, but sales
and trust building is
massive and epic. Highly
recommend. All right. News.
So news. The format
is just saying what
happened in the news
and then giving your
take on it. So
this is Tom. He's
been through the YouTube
growth system. He has
the luxury of Trump
doing all sorts of
things, which means he
can constantly jump on
a Trump story and
get way more views,
which can then grow
his business and his
channel. And then we
have Peter, who's also
in the YouTube growth
system. And what he's
done is taken an
Apple Notes update and
then showing people how
to use it, but
kind of packaged it
like it is news.
So the good thing
about news is, if
a story breaks in
your niche and you
cover it, you can
get really flipping fast
views and easy views
because there's suddenly a
huge spike in demand
for that sort of
content. It can set
you up as a
thought leader if your
take on it impresses
people. And what I
like about these is
at the end, you'll
funnel viewers back to
other types of videos
that are better for
conversion and building trust
and maybe a more
evergreen too. So you
can use it as
a way to get
new viewers and get
them into your system.
Cons, they're not evergreen.
Like I had a
friend whose entire channel
was news, and if
he didn't post videos
every day, his channel
went down to zero
views. This guy had
half a million subscribers
at that time. The
other con is if
a news story breaks,
you got to make
it quick. When I
was on film booth,
this news story broke.
So I got up
at 4 a .m.
I think I had
the video out by
like 3 in the
afternoon because I just
wanted to get it
and it was one
of my best viewed
videos of all time
at that stage. They're
not great for sales,
though. That's the other
side of this. At
the end of the
day, people come for
the news, not you.
So that's why. You
want to make sure
you push people back
to another video afterwards.
That is better for
sales. So they're fantastic
for views. If we're
going to score them,
not great for sales.
Trust building is OK.
Next type of video
is a case study.
You just show how
you or someone else
achieved an amazing result
that your viewers want
to. So this is
Daniel. He's been the
YouTube growth system. I
believe this video did
a quarter of a
million. I know it
hit 120 ,000. I
think that was a
quarter of a million
at the latest update.
This one here is
me. This. This literally
changed my life forever.
I just spoke about
how I monetize the
YouTube channel as fast
as I could, which
back then six weeks
was almost unheard of
and told the story.
This is my friend
Finzar. He does a
case study where he
goes editing undercover. It's
like a challenge where
he sees how much
he can makes. And
that's kind of the
name of the game.
So you don't have
to document it like
this big old story.
You can keep it
simple. But case studies
are insane for sales.
So if you tell
a client story, your
own, how you got
a result, it just
proves you're credible and
it differentiates you. Because
like I said, most
people are just going
to be copying other
people's content in this
game. When you find
that thing that differentiates
you and it pops,
you suddenly leap to
the top of the
niche and these can
get massive views. I'm
talking massive views. So
the cons are you
need to be very
good at storytelling to
pull this off. And
storytelling and getting good
at it is not
a beginner thing. It
can take years to
master. So I wouldn't
make this if I'm
a beginner. It also
requires a result that
surprises a viewer. So
if you just tell
a really predictable story
where the ending is
like, I could see
that coming, they don't
work. We need some
sort of twist to
really blow these bad
boys up. So if
I'm going to rate
them, they're just five
on everything. All right.
Interviews. You just interview
someone on your channel
who has some next
level information. Your viewers
will love. That's the
important bit. Next level.
All right. So this
video here. I interviewed
Andrew Kirby. As a
result, fifteen hundred people
joined his waitlist, which
is insane. Here someone's
interviewing Casey Neistat to
get his take on
filmmaking. Here we've got
someone interviewing David Goggins
to give his opinion
on something. So interviews,
the pros are they
are really fast and
easy to make because
you just ask someone
questions. Now you still
need to edit. You
still need to stick
to the template. I'm
going to teach you,
but they can be
much faster, can get
very strong views and
they harness someone else's
credibility. So you can
steal all their years
of work and whack
it on your channel.
Now, the problem is
they harness someone else's
credibility. What that means
is yours doesn't raise.
So as a result,
they are awful for
sales. I'm talking I
have interview videos of
three hundred and fifty
thousand views. And I
think I made one
sale from it. And
it also drove just
a ton of junk
inquiries and filled up
our calls with the
wrong people. So if
you are doing an
interview, you need to
make sure you're not
a silent partner. You
need to add some
sort of video. You
sort of value in
there, too. And I
wouldn't recommend doing every
video as an interview
because it's just it's
not going to grow
your business in the
same way as a
listicle with 10 percent
of the views will
so score views are
great. Sales are bad.
Trust building is kind
of lower on that
one, too. But Ed,
this stuff's not true.
Your ranking doesn't make
any sense because I've
seen these videos that
you say get low
views blow up and
yeah, that's how YouTube
works. This is kind
of a general overview,
but it's up to
you to test these
formats because we might
find a viewer roast,
which does bad for
me. It's like the
biggest video ever in
your niche. So just
keep that in mind.
So which one do
you pick? Well, we
fail as fast as
we can. We do
the research. I'm going
to teach you in
a minute. We pick
a format. We think
the viewers are going
to like we test
it. We measure we
learn a lesson and
then we ask, why
did that happen? And
then we repeat the
thing that works. That
is formats.
Now, let's move on
to researching to build
your video strategy.